<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component>
	<!-- COMPONENT NAME -->
	<name>TP4056 Li-Ion Battery Charger Circuit</name>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT IMAGES -->
	<image title="general">TP4056_charging_protector.jpg</image>
	<image title="thumbnail"></image>
	<!-- By interface we mean the specific parts on the component where connections are made -->
		
	
	<!-- COMPONENT PURPOSE -->
	<purpose>Used to charge the Lithium ion battery of the LPG.</purpose>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT PROPERTIES -->
	<properties>
		<property title="overCharge">Overcharge protection - the module will safely charge your battery to 4.2V</property>
		<property title="chageCurrent"> Programmable Charge Current Up to 1000mA</property>
		<property title="mosfet">No MOSFET, Sense Resistor or Blocking Diode Required</property>
		<property title="packaging">Available Radiator in 8-Lead SOP Package, the Radiator need connect GND or impending</property>
	</properties>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT DESCRIPTION -->
	<description>
		This module uses the TP4056 Li-Ion charge controller IC and a separate protection IC. 
        There are other types of modules on the market that use the TP4056 but lack any protection circuits or ICs to provide the necessary protection needed with lithium batteries. 
        This module uses both the TP4056 and the DW01A Li-Ion battery protection IC, which together in combination provide the following protection features:
        Can be powered, for charging, from a micro USB cable or the + and - connections, see Power Supply Options Diagram below. The power source needs to be able to provide at least 1A for the charger to correctly charge a connected battery. 
        Most modern phone/USB chargers can provide 1A or more; refer to the label on your phone charger to verify. 
        If you use the micro USB connection, be sure to use a USB cable that is made to carry at least 1A.
	</description>
	
	<!-- LINK TO COMPONENT'S DETAILS ONLINE -->
	<link>https://www.addicore.com/TP4056-Charger-and-Protection-Module-p/ad310.htm</link>
	
</component>
