<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component>
	<!-- COMPONENT NAME -->
	<name>I2C Cable</name>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT IMAGES -->
	<image title="general">i2c_cable.png</image>
	<image title="thumbnail"></image>
	<!-- By interface we mean the specific parts on the component where connections are made -->
		
	
	<!-- COMPONENT PURPOSE -->
	<purpose>
		Used for connecting to male pins for I2C chanel. For example, connecting the SHT25 (Temperature and Relative Humidity) daughter card to the I2C channel on the RSS2 mote.
	</purpose>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT PROPERTIES -->
	<properties>
		<property title="f2f">Female to female leads</property>
		<property title="GND">Ground wire</property>
		<property title="SCL">Serial Clock wire (SCL)</property>
		<property title="SDA">Serial Data wire (SDA)</property>
		<property title="VCC">Voltage at the Common Collector (VCC). power supply voltage.</property>
	</properties>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT DESCRIPTION -->
	<description>
		An Inter-Integrated Circuit (I2C) bus uses two lines, serial data (SDA) and
		serial clock (SCL), to transfer information between devices connected tothe bus. I2C devices have open-drain outputs. 
		When an I2C device drives a low, the output of the devices pulls the bus to ground. 
		When an I2Cdevice switches high, the output of the device goes into a high-Z state where the bus is pulled up to VDD by a pull-up resistor connected between the bus and VDD. 
		The pull-up resistors along with the capacitance of the cabling or bus creates a charging RC time constant. 
		If using off board cabling or very long buses, the total bus capacitance increases, which increases the rise time of the signal and reduces maximum operating frequency. 
		The total bus capacitance also increases with the number of devices connected to the bus.
	</description>
	
	<!-- LINK TO COMPONENT'S DETAILS ONLINE -->
	<link>https://www.analog.com/media/en/technical-documentation/technical-articles/I2C-Cabling.pdf</link>
	
</component>
