<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component>
	<!-- COMPONENT NAME -->
	<name>Soil Temperature Sensor</name>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT IMAGES -->
	<image title="general">soil_temperature_sensor.png</image>
	<image title="thumbnail"></image>
	<!-- By interface we mean the specific parts on the component where connections are made -->
		
	
	<!-- COMPONENT PURPOSE -->
	<purpose>Purpose Here</purpose>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT PROPERTIES -->
	<properties>
		<property title="rh_callibration">Fully Callibrated with 1.8% RH accuracy</property>
		<property title="i2c">Digital output with I2C interface</property>
		<property title="power">Low power consumption</property>
		<property title="durability">Excellent long term stability</property>
		<property title="reflow">DFN type package - reflow solderable.</property>
	</properties>
	
	<!-- COMPONENT DESCRIPTION -->
	<description>
		SHT25, the new humidity and temperature sensor of Sensirion is about to set new standards in terms of size and intelligence: Embedded in a reflow solderable Dual
		Flat No leads (DFN) package of 3 x 3mm foot print and 1.1mm height it provides calibrated, linearized signals in digital, true I2C format.
		With a completely new designed CMOSens® chip, a reworked capacitive type humidity sensor and an improved band gap temperature sensor the performance
		has been lifted even beyond the outstanding level of the previous sensor generation (SHT1x and SHT7x).
		For example, measures have been taken to stabilize the behavior at high humidity levels.
		Every sensor is individually calibrated and tested. Lot identification is printed on the sensor and an electronic identification code is stored on the chip – which can be
		read out by command. Furthermore, the resolution of SHT25 can be changed by command (8/12bit up to 12/14bit for RH/T), low battery can be detected and a
		checksum helps to improve communication reliability. 
		With made improvements and the miniaturization of the sensor the performance-to-price ratio has been improved– and eventually, any device should benefit from the cutting edge energy saving operation mode. 
		For testing SHT25 a new evaluation Kit EK-H4 is available.
	</description>
	
	<!-- LINK TO COMPONENT'S DETAILS ONLINE -->
	<link>https://cdn.sos.sk/productdata/bf/f4/e1c6ad4c/sht-25.pdf</link>
	
</component>